Inventory of the Obelia "Bee" Graves Papers 1936-1945
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Obelia "Bee" Graves Papers 1936-19451937-1939
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss. Acc. 2008.123
0.50
This collection contains letters to Obelia "Bee" Graves, from her family and friends, while she attended Winston-Salem Teachers College in Winston-Salem, North Carolina. The institution is presently known as Winston-Salem State University. Winston-Salem Teachers College was the first historically black college to grant bachelors degrees in elementary school education. The collection also includes college documents from her time at college such as report cards and her admission acceptance. The collection also contains letters from two soldiers to Bee Graves' sister, Cleonis. The soldiers served during World War II in the Philippines.
Graves, Obelia "Bee" arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
The materials were acquired by Special Collections Research Center on 11/25/2008.
Biographical Note
Obelia "Bee" Graves attended Winston-Salem Teachers College in Winston-Salem, North Carolina, the first historically black college to grant bachelor degrees in elementary school education. Her family lived in Blance, North Carolina.
Her parents were Vester and Sallie Graves. Further information about this individual or organization may be available in the Special Collections Research Center Wiki
Scope and Contents
This collection contains letters to Obelia "Bee" Graves, from her family and friends, while she attended Winston-Salem Teachers College in Winston-Salem, North Carolina. The institution is presently known as Winston-Salem State University. Winston-Salem Teachers College was the first historically black college to grant bachelors degrees in elementary school education. The collection also includes college documents from her time at college such as report cards and her admission acceptance. The collection also contains letters from two soldiers to Bee Graves' sister, Cleonis. The soldiers served during World War II in the Philippines.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence
Personal Name:
Education--North Carolina.
Topical Term:
African Americans; Women college students; World War, 1939-1945--Pacific Front
Detailed Description of the Collection
  Series 1: Letters from Family
- Letters from Family, 1937-1939
  - Letters from Vester Graves (Father), 1937-1938 (1)
    3 letters
  - Letters from Sallie Graves (Mother), 1937-1939 (2)
    4 letters
  - Letters from Cleonis Graves (Sister), 1937 (3)
    2 letters
  - Letters from Melba Graves (Sister), 1937-1938 (4)
  - Letter from Ella Graves (Sister), 1938 (5)
  - Letter from Lois Long (Cousin), 1937 (6)
  - Letters from Auntie Madie, 1937 (7)
  - Letters from Uncle Henry, 1937, 1939 (8)
  Series 2: Letters from Friends
- Letters from Friends, 1936-1939
  - Postcards from Friends, 1936-1939 (9)
  - Letters from Female Friends, 1936 (10)
  - Letters from Elbert Swann, 1936-1938 (11)
    1 of 2 folders; Elbert Swann appeared to have a crush on Bee Graves. He wrote ten letters to her, the most from one person in the collection.
  - Letters from Elbert Swann, undated (12)
    2 of 2 folders; Elbert Swann appeared to have a crush on Bee Graves. He wrote ten letters to her, the most from one person in the collection.
  - Letters from Louise Moore, 1937 (13)
  - Letters from Helen B., 1939 (14)
  - Letter from Walter (Boyfriend), 1938 (15)
  - Letters from C.L.B., Jr., 1936 (16)
  - Letters from J.B. Saunders, 1936, 1938 (17)
  - Letters from Male Friends, 1939 (18)
    These are friends from New York City.
  Series 3: Miscellaneous
- Miscellaneous
  Includes letters to Bee Graves's sister, Cleonis Graves, college documents, photographs
  - Letters from soldiers to Cleonis Graves (Sister), 1945 (19)
    This folder contains letters from two soldiers to Bee Graves' sister, Cleonis. The soldiers served during World War II in the Philippines.
  - Miscellaneous Items (20)
    This folder contains portrait photographs of unidentified people and letters.
  - College Documents, 1936-1940 (21)
    This folder contains documents relating to Bee Graves' tenure at Teachers College: room and board receipts, a report card, and insurance receipts. This is 1 of 2 folders.
  - College Documents, 1936-1940 (22)
    This folder contains an acceptance letter, a letter to Bee Graves' parents about Bee's progress and report cards. This is 2 of 2 folders.